Hello! In today's Bug Bounty Report Explained, you
will learn dependency confusion. It's a new hacking
technique that was revealed in 2021 and earned
the researcher much more than $130k.
The good news is that there are still hundreds of
thousands to be earned. Watch the video till the
end to get to know how to do it. The article was
originally published on Medium by Alex Birsan
Links, as always, are in the description. Enjoy!
Whencreating applications in any programming language,
we use many third-party libraries. They
are pieces of code written by other users.
And to use someone's library we must trust them
enough to run their code on our machine or on
our server. And there are tools that make using
other libraries easier like npm for javascript
pip for python or gem for ruby. In my examples, I
will mostly stick to python's pip because it's
probably what most of us is familiar with.
Whenyou want to install a library you run this command:
It may seem like this package is official or at
least verified by someone but it's not the case.
Everyone can create their package if
the name is not taken. You don't need
anything besides a free account on PyPi website
and organizing your project in specified structure.
Attacking libraries is not a new idea. For years
attackers have been creating malicious libraries
with mistyped names of popular packages,
creating malicious pull requests or somehow
gaining a maintainer status and
committing a bad code to known library.
However, this researcher found a new attack
vector which proved to be a goldmine.
When you are a big company many of your systems
do similar functionalities and integrate
with the same solutions. It means a lot of code
is rewritten or copied from product to project.
So to make things more efficient and secure,
you create private libraries that can be
then reused across the whole company. You
can't however publish this code to PyPi
because it's confidential. So you create a
private repository. Then, you can just add
--extra-index-url parameter to pip install and pip
will look there for the package you want to use.
There is also --index-url parameter. The difference
is that the former will look for the package
both in the public and in the private repository
while the latter will only look in the private one.
So when you have mixed public and private
dependencies you want to use --extra-index-url
The question is what would happen if both
the public and the private repository
would have the dependency that you want to
install. My logic would suggest that the package
from the private repository would have higher
priority, but it's not the case. Turns out that
pip chooses the library with the higher version.
And what's important, when publishing a new package
user can specify any version that he wants.
So if a company uses private python library
called company-authentication, anyone can go to
PyPi, create a public package with that name
and when someone in this company runs this command
to install the private dependency, the one created
by a malicious user from the public repository
will be downloaded, because it had higher version.
You then gain RCEs on servers, on CI/CD pipelines and even on developer PCs.
So the impact of this is even higher
than the impact of RCE in webapp,
because good webapps are created with the idea
in mind that there might be an RCE so the network
is separate from the corporate one, there are
least privileges and the traffic is also limited.
But executing code on developer PC
is a lovely spot to run ransomware.
That's the theory. Now, it was time for the
researcher to start practical attacks inas automated way as possible.
Whenhis malicious libraries were run,
he only collected system's username, hostname
and current path, so that he didn't possess
any very confidential information but
was still able to prove the vulnerability.
And when creating a library you can create a
script that will be executed upon installation,
before even executing the library. That's what he
used to send data back to him from those scripts.
However, a lot of servers use firewalls that
block outgoing HTTP traffic, so the researcher
exfiltrated data using DNS protocol. It's
normally used to resolve domain names
and it's rarely blocked by firewall. So his
scripts were trying to resolve domain names
with those exfiltrated information that were
also hex-encoded. The queries were eventually
reaching his DNS server, where he collected
all the data and inserted it into a database.
But now came the biggest challenge.
How to get those private package names?
First, the researcher targeted some companies
and tried to find their leaked names on GitHub,
on package hosting services or even
on different forums. But this approach
was very time-consuming not really efficient
and not at all automatable. The best source
turned out to be JavaScript files. Because
when you are creating a Node.js application,
some of the javascript code gets bundled into the
client-side javascript code which is of course
available to the user. And npm uses package.json
file to store those dependency names
and apparently this file quite often
gets bundled into this client-side code.
And finding package names using this approach
was much better because it's fully automatable.
With help of his friend, Alex scanned
thousands of domains of targeted companies
that leaked hundreds of private package names.
Then, when having names of those private packages,
they created public ones with respective names
and waited to hear from the callback scripts.
Multiple RCEs on developer PCs. on-premise
and cloud servers and development pipelines.
At the moment of writing the article 35 companies
were affected. Good thing about such attack
is that it's usually big companies that use
private packages so most of the targets were big
corporations and good thing about big corporations
is that they have back bounty programs with big
payouts. And rewards for those reports were usually
maximum and sometimes even higher than maximum.
For example, Shopify was pwned with shopify-cloud library and paid $30k.
Another $30k came from Apple
and yet another one from Paypal. The biggest reward
however came from Azure which paid $40k. So in total we have $130k
and it's only 4 out of 35
companies. The author also mentioned that he pwned
Netflix, Yelp and Uber. If they would also pay
their respective maximums we would have another $85khere.
It would be a total of $215kfor 7 out of 35 companies. Huge congratulations
to the author from me. I think we have a strong
contender for 2021 hacking technique here.
The researcher only focused on npm, pip and
gem, but 75% of all callbacks came from
javascript libraries. Was the difference such big
because of higher error rate in this technology?
Likely - no. The reason is that for javascript it was
the easiest to find package names. For example, for
RubyGems, the researcher only found packages
of 8 organizations out of which 4 were pwned.
It means if you only knew those
names you could make good money yourself.
And there are still many unexplored
areas in other programming languages.
And keep in mind that the researcher pwned
35 companies which is a huge achievement,
but it's not a big number compared to the
amount of bug bounty programs out there.
That's why I think there is still a lot of
money to be earned with dependency confusion.
And that's it. It's by far the highest reward for a
bug covered on my channel. I hope that some of you
will also be able to report a few dependency
confusion vulnerabilities. Let me know in the
comment section if you will. Anyway, if you
feel like you've learned something new today,
leave a like and leave a subscription!
Thanks for watching and goodbye!